乔伊，快说啦
Come on,Joey!
我知道的部分昨晚都告诉你了
I told you everything I knew last night.
没什么大不了的，反正他俩也做了
It's not that big a deal. So they're doing it.
你居然这么说
I cannot believe you would say that!
抱歉 莫妮卡和钱德在“做爱”
Sorry. Monica and Chandler are "making love."
不是啦，我是说这是大事耶
No,I mean,come on. This is a huge deal!
我想知道细节 是谁先吻谁的？
I need more details. Who initiated the first kiss?
不知
I don't know.
我无法想像钱德浪漫的样子
God,I just can't imagine Chandler being romantic.
他跟她在一起时浪漫吗？
Is he romantic with her?
不知
I don't know.
他们相爱吗？
Are they in love?
不知
I don't know.
你什么都不知道
You don't know anything.
我知道一件事 什么事？
I know one thing.What？
他们在这张沙发上做过
They did it right there.
本集播出：“钱德的工作笑容”
The One With Chandler's Work Laugh
主演：珍妮佛安妮斯顿
寇妮考克斯
丽莎库桌
麦特勒布蘭
马修派瑞
大卫修蒙
（中央咖啡馆）
罗斯
Ross
甘瑟，给我一个英式松饼
Could I have a scone?
想听好消息吗？
-Want to hear some good news?
有别人要说吗？ 你不像有好消息的样子
-ls somebody else gonna give it to us?Because you certainly don't seem like you have any.
不，我有 我认识的某人要结婚了
No,I do. Someone I know is getting married.
婚礼是最开心的场合
Weddings are happy occasions.
对了，那人是我的前妻艾蜜莉
Oh,it's my ex-wife,Emily!
什么？ 怎么会这样
Sorry,man.
你的英式松饼
-Here's your scone.
谢谢
-Thanks.
白痴英国点心！
Stupid British snack food!
那是情绪管理课教的吗？
Did they teach you that in anger management?
我有个办法，你就这么想
You know what might help you deal with it?
你和艾蜜莉已经过去了 你不能对过去的事生气
You two are in the past. You can't be mad about the past.
你还在气美国跟法国买路易斯安那州吗？
Are you still mad about,you know,the Louisiana Purchase?
菲比，没有人在气那个
Nobody's mad about that.
没错，因为已经过去了
Exactly! Because it's in the past.
那个有人要吃吗？
Anybody going to eat that?
我们盛装参加公司宴会耶
Look at us all dressed up for the party.
是在庆祝什么？ 圣诞晚会剩了不少酒
What are we celebrating?We had a lot of liquor left over from Christmas.
真好，这里没有我们的朋友 我们可以公开，不必躲躲藏藏
Our friends aren't here. We can be a real couple. We don't have to hide.
没错，我可以这样
I know. I can do this.
而我可以这样
And I can do this.
我们不能那样
We can't do that.
宾
Hey,Bing!
这位美女是谁 怎么跟你在一起？
Who's the pretty lady,and what is she doing with you?
我也这样问自己 这是莫妮卡，我上司道格
I asked myself that very question,sir.
道格，这是莫妮卡
My boss,Doug.-This is Monica.
幸会 这是我老婆卡拉
-Hi.-This is my wife,Kara.
很高兴认识你莫妮卡…宾
-Nice to meet you Monica.Bing
公司找了新法律顾问公司 是吗？
Did you hear about the new law firm working for us?
“侦查他，揍他，然后跑”（其实是“杜威-奇特姆-豪”事务所）
Dickem,Stickem & Run.
我们去喝个痛快
Let's go drink our body weight.
那是什么？ 什么？
What was that?What？
你刚才发出的声音 那是我的工作笑
That noise you made?Oh,my work laugh.
你的工作笑？
Your work laugh?
相信我，想熬过这场派对 你也得学着做
If you're going to survive this party,come up with one too.
好，看我的 好
All right. Check me out.
…30块钱，跟城里一样
He says,"$30,Father. Same as in town."
昨晚公司的人都好喜欢你
Everybody at work loved you last night.
真的？ 而且他们因为你而更喜欢我
And they like me more just because I was with you.
你弥补了不少乔伊造成的伤害
You repaired the damage from when they met Joey.
道格还找我们打网球 他出了公司还没理过我
Doug wants to play tennis. He never talks to me outside of work.
除了在脱衣舞夜总会那次
Except for that time at that strip club.
脱衣舞教堂
Strip church.
我要去找一支球拍 你不是有一支？
-I'll go find a racket. -I thought you had one.
后来被乔伊拿去中央公园 对着石头打…
I used to,but then Joey thought it'd be fun to go hit rocks...
大石头
...at bigger rocks.
瑞秋，你有网球拍吗？
Do you have a tennis racket?
我借给乔伊就没拿回来过
I lent it to Joey,and I've never gotten it back.
祝你的球拍好运
Good luck with that.
你好吗？
What's up?
你怎么来了？今天你们不是要盘点吗
Why are you here? I thought you had inventory.
没错，但我决定午休久一点 陪陪我的朋友莫妮卡
I do,but I decided I'd take a long lunch...and spend some time with my friend Monica.
我们现在都不谈心了
You know,I feel like we don't talk anymore.
你好吗？有什么新变化？
How are you?What is new with you?
不多，工作很顺利
Not much. Work's good.
我们不必聊工作 什么都可以聊
We don't have to talk about work. Talk about anything.
好吧…
Okay
这样吧，我们来聊感情的事
You know what?Let's talk about relationships.
好，你最近怎样？ 没人追
What's going on?Nothing.
该你
You go.
我原本觉得银行有一个人很帅 现在不觉得了
There was this guy at the bank that I thought was cute.But I don't anymore.
真精彩
That's juicy.
不过我确实很忙 你确定没别的了？
You know what? I actually do have a lot of work to do.You're sure there's just not anything else?
确定，你有什么事想说吗？ 没有
I'm sure. Is there something you want to talk to me about?No!
好吧，有也不告诉你
If there was,I wouldn't tell you.
好，然后呢？
Then what happened?
待会才轮到你
You'll get your turn.
菲比，在干什么？ 没什么
-Hey,Phoebe. What's going on? -Nothing.
还没完
This is not over.
糟糕 怎么了？
No,no,no!What？
我熬了一整晚写信骂艾蜜莉
I was up all night writing this nasty letter to Emily.
原本写得很好，现在沾满了…
It was perfect,and now it's all covered in....
事实上，谢谢
Actually,thanks!
可以去看电影了吗？
All right! Ready to go to the movies?
我想我不去了
Actually,I think I'll skip it.
你不去？ 对，我要留下来看书
Really?I'll read my book.
我现在只想静一静
I just want to be alone right now.
你真的不去？
Sure you don't want to?
汤姆汉克斯，梅格瑞恩 写信什么的（《电子情缘》）
Tom Hanks,Meg Ryan. They get mail and stuff.
我还是不去了
That's okay,Joe.
好吧，菲比我们走
Let's go,Phoebe.
好恶
Oh，God
宾
Bing
赢了
Game!
说真的，你的搭档真是只老虎
I got to tell you,that partner of yours is a real tiger.
你还好吗？
Are you all right?
我们喝口水
We'll just get a little sip of water.
我今天很猛吧？
Am I on fire today or what?
那两支肉鸡已经烤好 等着被切来吃了
Those birds are browned,basted and ready to be carved.
别激动，玛蒂娜（玛蒂娜·辛吉斯-网球名将）
Okay,easy,Martina.
我觉得下一场应该让他们赢
I think we should let them win the next game.
对不起，你刚说的话我听不懂
I'm sorry,I don't understand what you just said.
让他们赢一场
Let them win one.
你疯了吗？他们任我们宰割
Are you crazy? We own those two.
你看他们 他喘不过气来，她在吃药
Look at them!He can't even breathe,and she's popping pills.
你根本不给他们机会 他们有球拍不是吗？
You're not giving them a chance.They have rackets.
宾，我想打完这场就收了
We'll make this the last game.
了解，我求之不得 你真的没打过职业比赛？
Yes,sir. Put me out of my misery.Are you sure you never played pro?
拜托让他们赢
Please let them win.
我顶多只能把战斗力降到95%
I'll take it down to 95%,but that's the best I can do.
糟糕，漏掉了 我来
-Missed it! -I got it!
好球
Nice shot.
我来
I got it!
出界
Long!
你居然让他们赢
I can't believe you let them win.
至少你把不爽掩饰得很好
Well,at least you hid your feelings well about it.
我很沮丧
I was frustrated.
这是我的球拍 是你让我沮丧
It's my racket.Frustrated with you!
如果没输那场球 他们也不会找我们去吃饭
If we hadn't lost,they would never have invited us to dinner tomorrow.
我最困扰的是 你在他们身边整个人都变了
What bothers me...is how different you act around them.
故意输球，工作笑
The throwing the tennis games,the fake laugh...
“以后见，宾” “除非之前见你，道格”
...the "See you later,Bing!" "Not if I see you first,Doug!"
我哪有笑得像喝醉的海盗
Listen,I don't sound like some crazed,drunken pirate.
你没有，但工作的钱德有
I know you don't,but "work Chandler" does.
我不喜欢工作的钱德 那家伙是个马屁精
I don't like work Chandler. The guy's a suck-up.
因为你这些话 我晚上不跟你玩了
Because you said that...I'm not putting out tonight!
绝对有问题 我哥从来不彻夜不归
Something's wrong. My brother doesn't stay out all night.
也许应该去看看垃圾槽
Maybe we should check the trash chute.
罗斯挤不进垃圾槽
Ross couldn't fit down the trash chute.
没错，就差那么一点点
That's right. He almost could.
所以我之前卡住过
Which is exactly how I got stuck there.
他回来了 天哪
Oh,my God!
你死哪去了？
Where the hell have you been?
就是去外面了
Just,you know,out.
外面，天哪 我们怎么没去那里找
Oh,out! God,I don't know why we didn't think to check there.
你都在做什么？
What were you doing?
我先去喝酒，然后就随处晃了一下
I went to a bar,and then...I just walked around for a while.
你整夜一个人在外面乱晃？
You walked around all night in the city by yourself?
他做了，他跟某人做了
He hooked up!He hooked up with someone.
我不必回答你们的问题
I don't have to answer your questions.
我是个大人，爱怎样就怎样
I'm a big boy.I can do what I want.
他做了
He hooked up!
聊聊她嘛
Tell us about her!
罗斯，你把围巾掉在…
Ross,you left your scarf
你们好
Hey,you guys.
好，我知道你们在想什么
I know what you all are thinking,
但钱德在也门
but Chandler is in Yemen.
我还年轻，我有需求 我不能等一辈子
I'm a young woman. I have needs. I can't wait forever.
我也是这么想的
Yeah,that's what I was thinking.
所以我求求你们 在批评我之前先想一下
So I'm asking you,please,just take a moment before you judge me.
没有人在批评你
Nobody's judging you.
你，天时地利人和先生
Mr. Right-place-at-the-right-time...
跟我联络
...call me.
看来你的书看完了
So I guess you finished your book.
有点闲是吧？
Had some time on our hands,did we?
我知道你们要说什么…
I know what you guys are going to say.
你们的孩子会毛茸茸的
You two would have very hairy children.
我不知道你会说那个
I didn't know you'd say that.
罗斯，珍妮丝耶？
Ross! Janice?
等一下… 这是罗斯，他是我们的朋友
All right. Hold on,hold on.This is Ross.He's our friend.
他显然是疯了，脑筋秀逗了
He obviously went crazy.He obviously lost his mind.
没那么夸张，好吗？ 但是珍妮丝耶
Look,it's not that crazy. Okay?But it's Janice!
她是…珍妮丝耶
I mean,she's...Janice!
你醉得太离谱了
How drunk were you?
珍妮丝和我有很多共同点
Janice and I have a lot in common.
我们都离过婚，我们都有小孩
We've both been divorced. We both have kids.
你真的要再见她？ 菲比，别影响他
Are you going to see her again?-Don't put ideas in his head!
我确实要再见她 该死，菲比
-I will see her.Damn it,Phoebe!
我要说出一件我没坦承过的事 高中时
I have to tell you something that I've never admitted.In high school,
我知道你喜欢詹姆法洛 但我还是跟他上了床
I made out with James even though I knew you liked him.
哇，说出来的感觉真好 好，该你了
That feels so good to get off my chest. Okay,you go.
该我了？什么意思？
My turn? What are you talking about?
莫妮卡，我知道你和钱德的事
Monica，I know about you and Chandler.
什么？ 我那天听到你们在讲电话
What？I overheard you on the phone the other day.
你说“我会告诉瑞秋” “我要花两个小时洗衣服”
You said,"I'll tell Rachel I'm doing laundry for a couple of hours."
他说“洗衣服？” “那是我的新绰号吗？”
And he said,"Laundry? Is that my new nickname?"
然后你说“不是” “你明知你的绰号是大雕”
And you said:"No，You know what your nickname is,Mr. Big."
原来你正在写剧本 记得把结局告诉我
You're writing yourself a little play there,Rach.Let me know how it turns out.
我不知道 因为我吓到把电话挂掉了
I wouldn't know,because I got so freaked out I hung up the phone.
如果你听完 你会听到我是叫他…偏执狂先生
Well,if you had kept listening...you would have heard me call him Mister Bigot.
什么？ 偏执狂先生
What？Mr. Bigot.
他喜欢讲种族偏见的笑话
He tells the most racist jokes.
好，所以就这样 你是说你和钱德之间没什么
All right. So that's it.There's nothing going on between you and Chandler?
我和钱德？
Me and Chandler?
拿出20元来 先找到零食的赢，好吗？
Put your $20 down.First one to find the tasty treat wins,okay?
好，请参赛者从休息室出场
All right,let's get the contestants out of their isolation booths.
它们出场了
And they're off!
别挡住我的参赛者，裁判
Get your foot off my contestant! Judge?
裁判判定没有违规
Judge rules,no violation.
你们好
Hi guys
说也奇怪 我今天跟珍妮丝过得很开心
It's so weird to say this,but I just had a great date with Janice.
什么？ 真的假的？
-What? -Are you serious?
没错，我跟她诉说近来的惨事 我说了好几个小时
I opened up to her about all the stuff that's been happening to me.I mean,I talked for hours.
有人专心听你倾诉的感觉真好
It is amazing to have someone give you such focused attention.
那你何必找她，你有我们
You don't need Janice for that. You've got us.
鸭子找到花生酱饼干了 不
The duck gets the Nutter Butter!
那不是花生酱饼干 那是一颗馄饨
That's not a Nutter Butter. That's an old won ton!
裁判判定：是花生酱饼干
Judge rules...Nutter Butter.
真难判 是啊
Tough call.
但我们应该支持克林顿总统（希拉里·克林顿） 和她的老公比尔（比尔·克林顿）
Seriously,I strongly believe that we should support President Clinton...and her husband,Bill.
你们的咖啡要怎么上？
How do you like your coffee?
我不要，谢谢 我要一点点糖
-None for me. -A little sugar.
那就让莫妮卡把指头伸进去 应该就会甜了
I'll have Monica stick her finger in it. That will sweeten it up.
你那样笑怎么不会头痛？ 久了就习惯了
-That laugh doesn't give you a headache? -You get used to it.
我不觉得我会习惯 我以后不会用这一套
I don't think that I can.This will be it for me on the work things
老板说笑我就笑，这有什么吗
I laugh at my boss's jokes. What's the big deal?
如果能跟我尊敬的男友在一起 我干嘛陪一个没尊严的马屁精
I'd rather not be with this work-weasel guy...when I can be with my boyfriend,who I actually respect.
我得为卡拉煮的咖啡道歉
I got to apologize for Kara's coffee.
如果它去打架 连自己都保护不了
I'd feel sorry for it in a fight.It's not strong enough to defend itself.
你听到我的话了吗？ 什么？
Hear what I said?What？
那个笑话啊，你是怎么了？
It's a joke. What's the matter with you?
我只是觉得不好笑
Well,I just didn't think it was funny,sir.
你说什么？
Excuse me?
我只是… 亲爱的，我觉得你没听懂
-Well,I just -Honey?I just don't think you understood the joke.
是吗？ 是啊
Really?
很好笑耶，你一定是没听懂
I mean,it was really funny. I just don't think that you got it.
卡拉煮的咖啡很稀
You see,Kara's coffee is weak-tasting.
但道格是在暗示它很虚弱
But what Doug did was imply that it was weak physically.
现在你懂了吗？ 我懂了
-You get it now,honey? -I think I do!
谢谢你 我觉得你需要解释
-Thank you,Monica. -I thought you could use the help.
咖啡打架
Coffee in a fight!
瑞秋，我可以在这里看漫画吗
You mind if I read my comic books in here?
当然可以，怎么了？
Sure. Why?
钱德和莫妮卡在一起 我很难专心
Chandler and Monica are over there. It's kind of hard to concentrate.
什么？她刚打电话来说她要加班
She just called and said she was going to be working late.
她一直骗我 够了，我现在就过去揭穿他们
She keeps lying to me.That's it! I'm going over there and confronting them right now.
去找小裤裤！
Panty raid.
所以我得讲种族偏见的笑话？
All right,so you're telling me that I have to tell racist jokes now?
对不起，我不太会圆谎
I'm just not very good at this.
我很不会骗人 我又很讨厌骗瑞秋
I'm a terrible liar. I hate having to lie to Rachel.
但我们还不能公开 我知道，只是…
-But we're not ready to tell yet. -I know.
从高中起我什么事都告诉瑞秋
Ever since high school,Rachel was the one person that I told everything to.
我好怀念那种感觉 她是我最要好的朋友
I miss that so much now.She's my best friend.
乔伊？
Joey？
天哪，瑞秋
Oh,my God,Rachel!
你怎么跑来这里？
What are you doing here?
我是…我来借这盏灯去…看书，看得更清楚些
Well,I actually came over here to borrow this lamp...to look at my books.You know,see them a little better
太好了
Okay,great.
我在钱德的房间里是因为… 我在帮忙打扫
Well,what I was doing in Chandler's room is that...I was cleaning it.
他付钱请我打扫
He pays me to clean it.
真是个赚零用钱的好办法
What a great way to make some extra pocket money.
之前我说要加班 是指我的新工作
When I said to you earlier that I was at work...I'm at my new work.
真不错，对吧？
Good enough. Right?
好，那…我要去看书了
I'll go look at my books.
好，我得去忙我的新工作了
Go get back to my new job.
好
Okay
恭喜你找到这份工作
Congratulations on your new job!
天哪，她可真好骗
Man,she is really gullible.
你们的咖啡 谢谢
-Here you go. -Thanks.
其实我该走了
-Actually,I should get going.
你确定？ 你想留多晚我都奉陪
-You're sure?I can stay out as late as you want.
我说过我为什么休长假吧？ 对，你说过
I told you I'm on sabbatical from work？Yes,yes. You did.
天呐！又怎么了？
-Oh,man! -What is wrong now?
我不是点的这个
This isn't what I ordered.
我的人生就不能顺利一点吗？
Man! Can't anything go right in my life?
先是我的婚姻破裂，然后…
First,my marriage falls apart,and then
我知道！然后你被赶出你家 你的工作没了
I know!You lose your apartment,you lose your job
你的前妻很快就再婚 现在咖啡又错了
...your ex-wife gets married so fast! And now the coffee!
罗斯，我们得谈一谈 好
We need to talk.
有时我觉得… 不…
-Sometimes I feel -No,no,don't.
是我要说
I'm going to talk.
我认为我们的美好时光 已经落日了
I believe...that the sun has set on our day in the sun.
什么？ 你是个很好的人
You're a very sweet person,Ross.
但是我没办法再听你哀叫下去了
Unfortunately...I just don't think I can take another second of you whining!
我跟你确认一下
Let me make sure I'm hearing this right.
你要跟我结束 因为我太会发牢骚？
You're ending this with me because...I'm too whiny?
你是说，我是这么的爱发牢骚
So you're saying...I've become so whiny...
我让你，珍妮丝… 觉得很烦
that l...annoy you...Janice.
没错 我…的…天哪
Well,yeah!Oh,my God!
你不要紧吧？ 现在不要紧了
Will you be okay?I am now.
看来三人里面已经两人出局了…乔伊
I guess that's two out of three..Joey!
我们得谈一谈 好
Dude,we got to talk.
我只是想趁你听说之前告诉你
I wanted to tell you something before you heard it from someone else.
希望不会太奇怪
I hope this isn't too weird,but...
我最近跟珍妮丝交往过
...I had a thing with Janice.
你不生气？ 我干嘛生气？
You're not mad?Why would I be mad?
因为这种事有它的道义在
Because there's certain rules about this kind of stuff.
不能追朋友的旧情人、心上人 或是有亲属关系的人
You don't fool around with your friends' ex-girlfriends...or possible girlfriends or girls they're related to.
我很生气
I am mad.
但是你知道吗？我要原谅你
But you know,I'm going to forgive you.
因为那样才叫兄弟
Because that's what friends do.
他们会原谅朋友 犯了你念的那串禁忌
They forgive their friends when they do everything you just said.
但是我要你记住我原谅了你
Thank you.But I want you to remember...that I forgave you.
好 我还要你记住我免费收留你
I also want you to remember that I let you live here rent-free.
好 我还要你记住我送你27块钱
All right.And I want you to remember that I gave you...twenty-seven dollars.
无条件奉送
No strings attached!
要是你记不住 我们应该写…我们写下来吧
If you can't remember that...we should write it down. Let's write it down!